smokingpipes.com 2019-07-19

# Privacy Policy

**Privacy Notice Table Of Contents:**

  * **Our Commitment To Privacy**
  * **The Information We Collect**
  * **How We Use Cookies**
  * **How We Use Your Information**
  * **Email Communication& Regular Product Updates**
  * **Our Use of Live Chat**
  * **Data Security& Storage**
  * **Use of Third Parties**
  * **Our Commitment To Children's Privacy**
  * **How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information**
  * **Your Rights**
  * **How To Contact Us**

**Our Commitment To Privacy**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally identifiable information may be requested. 

**The Information We Collect:**

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the www.smokingpipes.com website. We collect information in three primary ways, through the process of fulfilling an order (Order Fulfillment), during the account creation process (Account Creation), and through the normal use of Smokingpipes.com (Website Usage). 

**Order Fulfillment**

When a customer places an order with Smokingpipes.com we will collect the following information: 

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email Address
  * Phone Number
  * Credit / Debit Card Information
  * Age
  * Browser & Operating System
  * IP Address

This information is used solely for the purpose of completing an order. When a customer places an order we will utilize a 3rd party to process credit cards and to monitor for fraud. This information is only used for a single transaction and is not shared or used for any other purpose. 

When a customer opts in during the checkout process, their email address may be used to receive further marketing communications from Smokingpipes.com. A customer's email address will never be shared with a third party for any reason. 

**Account Creation**

When a customer creates an account with Smokingpipes.com we will collect the following information: 

  * Name
  * Email Address
  * User ID

In addition to this information, a customer may provide Smokingpipes.com with additional information as part of their user account. This information is not required to maintain a user account and will only be used for the purposes of maintaining a user account on Smokingpipes.com. The information collected may include: 

  * Screen Name _(Optional)_
  * Age _(Optional)_
  * Address _(Optional)_
  * Credit / Debit Card Information _(Optional)_
  * Phone Number _(Optional)_
  * Profile Photo _(Optional)_
  * About Me / Bio _(Optional)_

This information is used in the creation of a public profile and for the purpose of maintaining a user account. None of the information collected will be shared with a third party and will be used for the sole purpose of utilizing Smokingpipes.com. An Email Address will be used for marketing communications and can be used for authentication purposes by the user when signing in to Smokingpipes.com. 

**Website Usage**

Smokingpipes.com uses a combination of internal reporting tools and external reporting tools to monitor and measure website performance. As part of these tools, the following information will be collected: 

  * IP Address
  * Browser & Operating System

This data is used by Smokingpipes.com to monitor site performance and to measure the results of our marketing efforts. Smokingpipes.com uses Google Analytics as our web analytics program. You can find out more information on Google Analytics and how the [data is used here](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). 

**How We Use Cookies**

Smokingpipes.com use cookies to provide you with the best experience and a more customized service. Among other things, cookies allow you to log in, create a favorite list of Tobaccos and receive email alerts when an in stock notification criteria becomes available. This Cookie Policy explains what cookies are, how we use them and what benefits they bring. 

**What Is A Cookie?**

Cookies are small text files that are sent to and stored on your computer, smartphone or other device for accessing the Internet, whenever you visit a website. Each cookie is unique to your web browser. It will contain some anonymous information such as a unique identifier, the site name, and some digits and numbers. Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot be accessed by other servers, which means that they cannot be used to track your movements around the web. Passwords and credit card numbers are not stored in cookies. 

Most websites you visit will use cookies in order to improve your user experience by enabling that website to 'remember' you, either for the duration of your visit (using a 'session cookie') or for repeat visits (using a 'persistent cookie'). 

Smokingpipes.com use cookies for a variety of reasons, such as to determine preferences, Chat live with Customer Support, let users navigate between pages efficiently, verify the user and carry out other essential security. 

Cookies make the interaction between you and the website faster and easier. If a website doesn't use cookies, it will think you are a new visitor every time you move to a new page on the site - for example, when you enter your login details and move to another page it won't recognize you and it won't be able to keep you logged in.

Cookies may be set by the website you are visiting ('first party cookies') or they may be set by other websites who run content on the page you are viewing ('third party cookies'). 

We don't sell the information collected by cookies, nor do we disclose the information to third parties, except where required by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies). 

Opt Out Link <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

**How We Use Your Information**

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only to complete that order and to improve your shopping experience. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order. 

We use the information you provide about someone else when placing an order only to ship the product and to confirm delivery. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order. 

We offer gift-cards by which you can personalize a product you order for another person. Information you provide to us to create a gift-card is only used for that purpose, and it is only disclosed to the person receiving the gift. 

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. 

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website. 

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online. 

Further, we will never divulge personally identifying information without a court order. 

**Email Communication& Regular Product Updates**

When you register for an account on Smokingpipes.com you will receive regular updates about new products being added to our website as part of our service through the email address you provide at account creation. Smokingpipes.com uses MailChimp to send these regular communications. As part of our use of MailChimp, we will provide them with your email address and name. This information is only used for the purposes of email communication between the account holder (you) and Smokingpipes.com. This information is not shared with a third party or used for any other purposes other than to receive our regular communications. For more information on Mailchimp, [please visit this link](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). 

**Our Use of Live Chat**

As part of our commitment to offering the best customer experience possible, Smokingpipes.com offers a live chat option to communicate with our Customer Service department. Live chat is not required in order to communicate with Smokingpipes.com. When initiating a Live Chat session, a user will provide us with a Name and Email Address. This information is only used for the purpose of referencing account details and providing a method of identifying the person making the request. This information is not shared with a third party and is only used for the purposes of communicating with our Customer Service department. 

Smokingpipes.com uses Live Chat as our service provider. For more information on Live Chat, please [visit them here](https://www.livechatinc.com/). 

**Data Security& Storage**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

**Use of Third Parties**

Smokingpipes.com currently uses third party Subprocessors to provide infrastructure services, and to help us provide customer support and email notifications. Prior to engaging any third party Subprocessor, Smokingpipes.com performs due diligence to evaluate their privacy, security and confidentiality practices, and executes an agreement implementing its applicable obligations. 

The list of third parties used is:

Provider Name | Provider Type | Provider Location  
---|---|---  
Rackspace Inc. | Infrastructure Provider  | United States  
Google Inc. | Cloud Based Service Provider  | United States  
MailChimp Inc. | Cloud Based Email Service Provider | United States  
SendGrid Inc. | Cloud Based Email Notification Service  | United States  
Live Chat Inc. | Cloud Based Chat Service | United States  
  
**Our Commitment To Children's Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 18, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 18. 

**How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information**

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain by logging in with the username and password you chose during account creation. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. 

You can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request that credibly shows error. 

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. 

**Your Rights**

Individuals located in certain countries, including the European Economic Area, have certain statutory rights in relation to their personal data. Subject to any exemptions provided by law, you may have the right to request access to Information, as well as to seek to update, delete or correct this Information. You can do this by contacting Customer Service for additional access and assistance. 

To the extent that Smokingpipes.com's processing of your Personal Data is subject to the General Data Protection Regulation, Smokingpipes.com relies on its legitimate interests, described above, to process your data. Smokingpipes.com may also process Other Information that constitutes your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes and you have a right to object to Smokingpipes.com's use of your Personal Data for this purpose at any time. 

**How To Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please call us at (888) 366-0345 or send us an email at [info@smokingpipes.com](mailto:info@smokingpipes.com).
